# CARLA SCHERER

## Data Science & Al | Data Engineering

São Paulo, SP +55 51 993267470 carlatscherer@gmail.com Linked-In: carla-scherer-a4793b93/ GitHub: carlascherer

#### WHO AM I

I have a masters degree in Engineering with a focus on mathematical modelling of Structures. I have been studying to specialize in Data Science and AI field of knowledge and, for the past year, I have been working with OCR/IA using IBM Watson, among other technologies. I also have been studying to become certified in some Clouds, like Azure and Google. I appreciate working with technology because I get the chance to learn something new every day. It also enables me to help to solve problems using logic and exact sciences, something that motivates me. I am curious and like to understand how things work and why they are as they are. I also learn very fast because I am engaged and always try to push myself out of my comfort zone.



#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Accenture / Software Engineering Analyst

10/2020-Now

- Development of OCR/IA model to extract information of non-structured documents (text documents)
- Google Cloud Business Group member.

### RS Highways Company / Civil Engineer

07/2018-09/2020

- Coordination of signalling services in 900km of roads
- Planning and follow-up of the engineering services
- Automatization of day-to-day repetitive tasks

### **CORSAN / Civil Engineer**

02/2015-02/2016

- Elaboration of analysis reports
- Construction of budgets using VBA programming

#### **EDUCATION**

UFRGS, MSc. Civil Eng. - Structures

2016-2018

UFRGS, Civil Eng. | Electrical Eng. (Incomp.)

2009-2013 | 2007-2009

DIGITAL HOUSE, Full Stack Web Dev. | Data Science 2020-2021 | 2021-2021

ivity

### Progr. Lang./Libraries

- Python
- Pandas/Numpy
- Scikit-learn
- SQL
- JavaScript
- Express.JS
- HTML/CSS

#### Tools

- VS Code
- GCP
- Azure
- IBM Watson
- GCP AutoML
- Node.JS
- Git/GitHub
- Excel

### Knowledge

- Math/Stats
- Logic (progr)
- Cloud
- Web systems
- OCR/IA

#### Soft Skills

- Communication
- Colaboration
- Resilience
- Flexibility
- Creativity